<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="ethno">
        <item>
            The National Museum of Bulgarian Art is the largest and most respectable institution of its kind in Bulgaria.
            Over the years, it has established its position as a center for national cultural heritage and values.
            The collection was started in 1892 when the People’s Museum of Archeology founded its Department of Art.
            By virtue of an express resolution of the Council of Ministers in 1948 National Art Gallery
            was pronounced an independent entity.\nThe museum’s collection of New and Contemporary Bulgarian art
            from the period since Bulgaria’s Liberation in 1878 up to the 1990s consists of more than
            30 000 individual pieces of paintings, prints and sculptures. The collection of paintings by Bulgarian masters
            is the most comprehensive. The collection of black and white drawings is also very rich.
            The museum’s expositions feature some of the best achievements of Bulgarian sculptors of the 20th century.
            \nExpositions are regularly organized in the halls of the museum.
            There are about ten of them held here each year. They are usually dedicated to prominent Bulgarian artist or major issues in the
            New and Contemporary Bulgarian Art. Mixed expositions by various artists organized on regular basis
            illustrate the diversity of the artistic process from the first days of independence till the present.
        </item>
        <item>
            Working Hours: \n10 am to 6 pm;
            \nClosed: Monday;
        </item>
        <item>
            Prices:  Adults 6 BGN; \nStudents and seniors - 3 BGN; \nPeople with disabilities - admission free;
            \nLecture for group of 5 persons - 20 BGN;
            \nLecture for group of more than 5 persons - 30 BGN;
            \nTicket office closes at 5:30 pm.
        </item>
         <item>
            Phone: \n+359 2 9080093
        </item>
        <item>Address: Sofia, 1 Kniaz Alexandar I Sq.  <b>(Click to see on the map)</b></item>
        <item>@string/ethmo_link</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>